<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<vulnerabilities xmlns="http://tempuri.org/XMLSchemaOptions.xsd">

<vuln_items>wasc_1</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_1>
	<alert>不適切な認証</alert>
	<desc>不適切な認証は、あるWebサイトにおいて、攻撃者が機密性の高いコンテンツや機能に対して適切なアクセス許可なしにアクセス可能な際、発生します。 Web上の管理ツールは、機密性の高い機能へのアクセスを提供するWebサイトの良い例です。 ものによって、これらのWebアプリケーションは、適切な利用者の確認をユーザに要求せず、直接的にアクセス出来る状態ではいけません。

認証の設定を要領良く行うために、いくつかのリソースは特定の場所に「隠すこと」や、メインのWebサイトやその他の公共サイトにリンクを貼らないことで、保護されます。 ただし、この方法は「隠蔽によるセキュリティ」にしかすぎません。 あるリソースが、攻撃者に対して知られていない状態でさえも、特定のURLによって直接アクセス出来る状況のままであるということを理解することが重要です。 その特定のURLと言うものは、共通ファイルやディレクトリの配置（例えば、/admin）、エラーメッセージ、参照ログ、あるいはヘルプファイルのような文書を総当りで調査することで発見される可能性があります。 これらのリソースは、コンテンツや機能として使用される、されないに関わらず、適切に保護されるべきです。</desc>
	<solution>フェーズ： アーキテクチャと設計
認証フレームワーク、あるいはOWASP ESAPIの認証機能を持つようなライブラリを使用してください。</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Insufficient-Authentication</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/287.html</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/284.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_1>

<vuln_items>wasc_2</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_2>
	<alert>不適切な承認</alert>
	<desc>不適切な承認は、あるアプリケーションにおいて、セキュリティポリシーに準ずる一貫した体制のもと、ユーザが機能を実行、あるいはデータへアクセスすることを確認するための適切な承認チェックが行われない際に、発生します。 承認の手続きは、どのユーザ、サービス、あるいはアプリケーションが実行を許可されるかを確実にすべきです。 ユーザがあるWebサイトに対して承認された場合、そのユーザが全てのコンテンツや機能への全アクセス権限を持つべきだと言うことは必ずしもありません。

不十分な認証機能

多くのアプリケーションは、異なるユーザに異なるアプリケーション機能を付与します。 例えば、ニュースサイトでは、ユーザは記事を閲覧することは許可されますが、発行することは許可されません。 決済システムでは、お金を支払う人と受取とる人に異なるアクセス権限の許可が与えられます。 不適切な承認は、あるアプリケーションにおいて、セキュリティポリシーを破られ、ユーザがアプリケーション機能にアクセスすることを防止できない場合に発生します。

1つの良い例をあげるとすれば、2005年に起こったハーバード・ビジネス・スクールの事件でしょう。 承認の失敗によって、ユーザは、アクセス出来ないはずのWebサイトページの一部に、アクセスが出来ていました。
 
不十分なデータ認証

多くのアプリケーションは、URL内に存在するデータ情報を公開しています。 たとえば、以下のようなURLをもつ医療記録システムがあるかもしれません。

http://example.com/RecordView?id=12345

仮に、閲覧権限を持つ承認されたユーザIDをアプリケーションが確認しない場合、閲覧すべきでないデータが当該ユーザに表示される可能性があります。

不適切なデータの承認は、不適切な機能の承認よりも一般的です。なぜなら、プログラマーは通常、アプリケーション機能の完璧な知識はありますが、アプリケーションでアクセスされる、全データの完全な構造を常に把握している訳ではないからです。 プログラマーは、承認機能のアルゴリズムはきっちりと定義しますが、データの承認を行うデータベースなどは別のシステムに頼っています。</desc>
	<solution>フェーズ： アーキテクチャと設計；オペレーション
特に注意して、設定、マネジメント、および権限の操作を管理してください。 明確に、ソフトウェアの信頼範囲を管理してください。

フェーズ： アーキテクチャと設計
システム設計に組み込まれた適切な区分や、権限分離機能を強化・許可するサーバ区分を確認してください。 構築者や設計者は、システム権限を適切に使用、破棄する場合を決定する最低権限の原則を信頼すべきです。</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Insufficient-Authorization</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/284.html</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/285.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_2>

<vuln_items>wasc_3</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_3>
	<alert>整数オーバフロー</alert>
	<desc>整数オーバフローは、ある算出操作の結果において（たとえば掛け算、足し算）、値を保有する整数型の最大値を超えた場合に、発生します。 整数オーバフローが発生した際、その解釈された値は、最大値を「回り込ませ」、最小の値から再び開始させるように思えます。たとえば、時計で言うと13:00が1:00を指しているイメージに近いです。

具体例をあげると、多くの一般的なパソコン上において8bitの符号あり整数は、最大の値が127で、最小の値が-128です。 仮に、プログラマがある変数で127の値を保持し、それに1を加えると、計算結果は128になるべきでしょう。 しかしながら、この値は上記の整数型の最大値を超えているため、その解釈された値は「回り込み」、-128になります。</desc>
	<solution>フェーズ： 要件
全てのプロトコルは厳格に定義されている、領域を超えた全てのものは簡単に認識されているかを確認してください。プロトコルに対して、厳密な整合性を要求してください。

フェーズ： 要件
同脆弱性を引き起こさせない、あるいは容易に回避可能な言語を使用してください。
可能ならば、限界値の自動チェックを行う言語、あるいはコンパイラを選択してください。

フェーズ： アーキテクチャと設計
同脆弱性を引き起こさせない、あるいは容易に回避可能な精査されたライブラリ、あるいはフレームワークを使用してください。
予期しない結果が起こらない数値を容易に扱えるライブラリー、あるいはフレームワークを使用してください。
例として、SafeInt（C++）、IntegerLib（C、C++）のような、安全な整数を取り扱う処理があります。

フェーズ：　実装
予想される範囲を定め、特定の数値入力の検証を行ってください。 予想される範囲の最大と最小に適する入力を強制してください。
可能なところで、符号なし整数を使用してください。 これは、整数オーバフローの正当性チェックを実行しやすくなります。 符号なし整数を使用する必要がある場合は、最小値と最大値の範囲チェックが含まれていることを確認してください。

フェーズ： 実装
プログラミング言語の基になる表現と数値計算 (CWE-681) とがどのように影響し合うのかを理解してください。 バイトサイズの不一致、精度、符号付き/符号なしの区別、切り捨て、変換とキャストの種類、非数の計算や過大小数値の操作における基礎表現へ細心の注意を払ってください。
Also be careful to account for 32-bit, 64-bit, and other potential differences that may affect the numeric representation.

Phase: Implementation
Examine compiler warnings closely and eliminate potentially security critical problems, such as signed / unsigned mismatch. Even if the weakness is rarely exploitable, a single failure may lead to the compromise of the entire system.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Integer-Overflows</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/190.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_3>

<vuln_items>wasc_4</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_4>
	<alert>Insufficient Transport Layer Protection</alert>
	<desc>Insufficient Transport Layer Protection
Insufficient transport layer protection allows communication to be exposed to untrusted third-parties, providing an attack vector to compromise a web application and/or steal sensitive information. Websites typically use Secure Sockets Layer / Transport Layer Security (SSL/TLS) to provide encryption at the transport layer. However, unless the website is configured to use SSL/TLS and configured to use SSL/TLS properly, the website may be vulnerable to traffic interception and modification.
 
Lack of Transport Layer Encryption
When the transport layer is not encrypted, all communication between the website and client is sent in clear-text which leaves it open to interception, injection and redirection (also known as a man-in-the-middle/MITM attack). An attacker may passively intercept the communication, giving them access to any sensitive data that is being transmitted such as usernames and passwords. An attacker may also actively inject/remove content from the communication, allowing the attacker to forge and omit information, inject malicious scripting, or cause the client to access remote untrusted content. An attacker may also redirect the communication in such a way that the website and client are no longer communicating with each other, but instead are unknowingly communicating with the attacker in the context of the other trusted party.

Weak Cipher Support
Historically, high grade cryptography was restricted from export to outside the United States. Because of this, websites were configured to support weak cryptographic options for those clients that were restricted to only using weak ciphers. Weak ciphers are vulnerable to attack because of the relative ease of breaking them; less than two weeks on a typical home computer and a few seconds using dedicated hardware.
Today, all modern browsers and websites use much stronger encryption, but some websites are still configured to support outdated weak ciphers. Because of this, an attacker may be able to force the client to downgrade to a weaker cipher when connecting to the website, allowing the attacker to break the weak encryption. For this reason, the server should be configured to only accept strong ciphers and not provide service to any client that requests using a weaker cipher. In addition, some websites are misconfigured to choose a weaker cipher even when the client will support a much stronger one. OWASP offers a guide to testing for SSL/TLS issues, including weak cipher support and misconfiguration, and there are other resources and tools as well.</desc>
	<solution>Phase: Requirements
Clearly specify which data or resources are valuable enough that they should be protected by encryption. Require that any transmission or storage of this data/resource should use well-vetted encryption algorithms.

Phase: Architecture and Design
Using threat modeling or other techniques, assume that your data can be compromised through a separate vulnerability or weakness, and determine where encryption will be most effective. Ensure that data you believe should be private is not being inadvertently exposed using weaknesses such as insecure permissions (CWE-732).

Phase: Architecture and Design
Ensure that encryption is properly integrated into the system design, including but not necessarily limited to:
      Encryption that is needed to store or transmit private data of the users of the system
      Encryption that is needed to protect the system itself from unauthorized disclosure or tampering 
Identify the separate needs and contexts for encryption:
      One-way (i.e., only the user or recipient needs to have the key). This can be achieved using public key cryptography, or other techniques in which the encrypting party (i.e., the software) does not need to have access to a private key.
      Two-way (i.e., the encryption can be automatically performed on behalf of a user, but the key must be available so that the plaintext can be automatically recoverable by that user). This requires storage of the private key in a format that is recoverable only by the user (or perhaps by the operating system) in a way that cannot be recovered by others.

Phase: Architecture and Design
Do not develop your own cryptographic algorithms. They will likely be exposed to attacks that are well-understood by cryptographers. Reverse engineering techniques are mature. If your algorithm can be compromised if attackers find out how it works, then it is especially weak.

Phase: Architecture and Design
Select a well-vetted algorithm that is currently considered to be strong by experts in the field, and select well-tested implementations.
For example, US government systems require FIPS 140-2 certification.
As with all cryptographic mechanisms, the source code should be available for analysis.
Periodically ensure that you aren't using obsolete cryptography. Some older algorithms, once thought to require a billion years of computing time, can now be broken in days or hours. This includes MD4, MD5, SHA1, DES, and other algorithms which were once regarded as strong.

Phase: Architecture and Design
Compartmentalize your system to have "safe" areas where trust boundaries can be unambiguously drawn. Do not allow sensitive data to go outside of the trust boundary and always be careful when interfacing with a compartment outside of the safe area.

Phases: Implementation; Architecture and Design
When you use industry-approved techniques, you need to use them correctly. Don't cut corners by skipping resource-intensive steps (CWE-325). These steps are often essential for preventing common attacks.

Phase: Implementation
Use naming conventions and strong types to make it easier to spot when sensitive data is being used. When creating structures, objects, or other complex entities, separate the sensitive and non-sensitive data as much as possible.
This makes it easier to spot places in the code where data is being used that is unencrypted.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Insufficient-Transport-Layer-Protection</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/311.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_4>

<vuln_items>wasc_5</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_5>
	<alert>リモート ファイル　インクルージョン</alert>
	<desc>Remote File Include (RFI) is an attack technique used to exploit "dynamic file include" mechanisms in web applications. When web applications take user input (URL, parameter value, etc.) and pass them into file include commands, the web application might be tricked into including remote files with malicious code.

Almost all web application frameworks support file inclusion. File inclusion is mainly used for packaging common code into separate files that are later referenced by main application modules. When a web application references an include file, the code in this file may be executed implicitly or explicitly by calling specific procedures. If the choice of module to load is based on elements from the HTTP request, the web application might be vulnerable to RFI.
An attacker can use RFI for:
    * Running malicious code on the server: any code in the included malicious files will be run by the server. If the file include is not executed using some wrapper, code in include files is executed in the context of the server user. This could lead to a complete system compromise.
    * Running malicious code on clients: the attacker's malicious code can manipulate the content of the response sent to the client. The attacker can embed malicious code in the response that will be run by the client (for example, Javascript to steal the client session cookies).

PHP is particularly vulnerable to RFI attacks due to the extensive use of "file includes" in PHP programming and due to default server configurations that increase susceptibility to an RFI attack.</desc>
	<solution>Phase: Architecture and Design
When the set of acceptable objects, such as filenames or URLs, is limited or known, create a mapping from a set of fixed input values (such as numeric IDs) to the actual filenames or URLs, and reject all other inputs.
For example, ID 1 could map to "inbox.txt" and ID 2 could map to "profile.txt". Features such as the ESAPI AccessReferenceMap provide this capability.

Phases: Architecture and Design; Operation
Run your code in a "jail" or similar sandbox environment that enforces strict boundaries between the process and the operating system. This may effectively restrict which files can be accessed in a particular directory or which commands can be executed by your software.
OS-level examples include the Unix chroot jail, AppArmor, and SELinux. In general, managed code may provide some protection. For example, java.io.FilePermission in the Java SecurityManager allows you to specify restrictions on file operations.
This may not be a feasible solution, and it only limits the impact to the operating system; the rest of your application may still be subject to compromise.
Be careful to avoid CWE-243 and other weaknesses related to jails.
For PHP, the interpreter offers restrictions such as open basedir or safe mode which can make it more difficult for an attacker to escape out of the application. Also consider Suhosin, a hardened PHP extension, which includes various options that disable some of the more dangerous PHP features.

Phase: Implementation
Assume all input is malicious. Use an "accept known good" input validation strategy, i.e., use a whitelist of acceptable inputs that strictly conform to specifications. Reject any input that does not strictly conform to specifications, or transform it into something that does. Do not rely exclusively on looking for malicious or malformed inputs (i.e., do not rely on a blacklist). However, blacklists can be useful for detecting potential attacks or determining which inputs are so malformed that they should be rejected outright.
When performing input validation, consider all potentially relevant properties, including length, type of input, the full range of acceptable values, missing or extra inputs, syntax, consistency across related fields, and conformance to business rules. As an example of business rule logic, "boat" may be syntactically valid because it only contains alphanumeric characters, but it is not valid if you are expecting colors such as "red" or "blue."
For filenames, use stringent whitelists that limit the character set to be used. If feasible, only allow a single "." character in the filename to avoid weaknesses such as CWE-23, and exclude directory separators such as "/" to avoid CWE-36. Use a whitelist of allowable file extensions, which will help to avoid CWE-434.

Phases: Architecture and Design; Operation
Store library, include, and utility files outside of the web document root, if possible. Otherwise, store them in a separate directory and use the web server's access control capabilities to prevent attackers from directly requesting them. One common practice is to define a fixed constant in each calling program, then check for the existence of the constant in the library/include file; if the constant does not exist, then the file was directly requested, and it can exit immediately.
This significantly reduces the chance of an attacker being able to bypass any protection mechanisms that are in the base program but not in the include files. It will also reduce your attack surface.

Phases: Architecture and Design; Implementation
Understand all the potential areas where untrusted inputs can enter your software: parameters or arguments, cookies, anything read from the network, environment variables, reverse DNS lookups, query results, request headers, URL components, e-mail, files, databases, and any external systems that provide data to the application. Remember that such inputs may be obtained indirectly through API calls.
Many file inclusion problems occur because the programmer assumed that certain inputs could not be modified, especially for cookies and URL components.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Remote-File-Inclusion</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/98.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_5>

<vuln_items>wasc_6</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_6>
	<alert>書式文字列攻撃</alert>
	<desc>Format String Attacks alter the flow of an application by using string formatting library features to access other memory space. Vulnerabilities occur when user-supplied data are used directly as formatting string input for certain C/C++ functions (e.g. fprintf, printf, sprintf, setproctitle, syslog, ...).

If an attacker passes a format string consisting of printf conversion characters (e.g. "%f", "%p", "%n", etc.) as a parameter value to the web application, they may:
    * Execute arbitrary code on the server
    * Read values off the stack
    * Cause segmentation faults / software crashes

Format String attacks are related to other attacks in the Threat Classification: Buffer Overflows and Integer Overflows. All three are based in their ability to manipulate memory or its interpretation in a way that contributes to an attacker's goal.</desc>
	<solution>Phase: Requirements
Choose a language that is not subject to this flaw.

Phase: Implementation
Ensure that all format string functions are passed a static string which cannot be controlled by the user and that the proper number of arguments are always sent to that function as well. If at all possible, use functions that do not support the %n operator in format strings.
Build: Heed the warnings of compilers and linkers, since they may alert you to improper usage.
</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Format-String</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/134.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_6>

<vuln_items>wasc_7</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_7>
	<alert>バッファ オーバーフロー</alert>
	<desc>A Buffer Overflow is a flaw that occurs when more data is written to a block of memory, or buffer, than the buffer is allocated to hold. Exploiting a buffer overflow allows an attacker to modify portions of the target process’ address space. This ability can be used for a number of purposes, including the following:
    * Control the process execution
    * Crash the process
    * Modify internal variables

The attacker’s goal is almost always to control the target process’ execution. This is accomplished by identifying a function pointer in memory that can be modified, directly or indirectly, using the overflow. When such a pointer is used by the program to direct program execution through a jump or call instruction, the attacker-supplied instruction location will be used, thereby allowing the attacker to control the process.

In many cases, the function pointer is modified to reference a location where the attacker has placed assembled machine-specific instructions. These instructions are commonly referred to as shellcode, in reference to the fact that attackers often wish to spawn a command-line environment, or shell, in the context of the running process.

Buffer overflows are most often associated with software written in the C and C++ programming languages due to their widespread use and ability to perform direct memory manipulation with common programming constructs. It should be emphasized, however, that buffer overflows can exist in any programming environment where direct memory manipulation is allowed, whether through flaws in the compiler, runtime libraries, or features of the language itself.
</desc>
	<solution>フェーズ： 要件
同脆弱性を引き起こさせない、あるいは容易に回避可能な言語を使用してください。
For example, many languages that perform their own memory management, such as Java and Perl, are not subject to buffer overflows. Other languages, such as Ada and C#, typically provide overflow protection, but the protection can be disabled by the programmer.
Be wary that a language's interface to native code may still be subject to overflows, even if the language itself is theoretically safe.

フェーズ： アーキテクチャと設計
同脆弱性を引き起こさせない、あるいは容易に回避可能な精査されたライブラリ、あるいはフレームワークを使用してください。
Examples include the Safe C String Library (SafeStr) by Messier and Viega, and the Strsafe.h library from Microsoft. These libraries provide safer versions of overflow-prone string-handling functions. This is not a complete solution, since many buffer overflows are not related to strings.

Phase: Build and Compilation
Run or compile your software using features or extensions that automatically provide a protection mechanism that mitigates or eliminates buffer overflows.
For example, certain compilers and extensions provide automatic buffer overflow detection mechanisms that are built into the compiled code. Examples include the Microsoft Visual Studio /GS flag, Fedora/Red Hat FORTIFY SOURCE GCC flag, StackGuard, and ProPolice.

Phase: Implementation
Consider adhering to the following rules when allocating and managing an application's memory:
      Double check that your buffer is as large as you specify.
      When using functions that accept a number of bytes to copy, such as strncpy(), be aware that if the destination buffer size is equal to the source buffer size, it may not NULL-terminate the string.
      Check buffer boundaries if calling this function in a loop and make sure you are not in danger of writing past the allocated space.
      If necessary, truncate all input strings to a reasonable length before passing them to the copy and concatenation functions.

Phase: Operation
Use a feature like Address Space Layout Randomization (ASLR).

Phase: Operation

Use a CPU and operating system that offers Data Execution Protection (NX) or its equivalent.

Phase: Implementation

Replace unbounded copy functions with analogous functions that support length arguments, such as strcpy with strncpy. Create these if they are not available.
</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Buffer-Overflow</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/119.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_7>

<vuln_items>wasc_8</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_8>
	<alert>クロスサイト スクリプティング(XSS)</alert>
	<desc>Cross-site Scripting (XSS) is an attack technique that involves echoing attacker-supplied code into a user's browser instance. A browser instance can be a standard web browser client, or a browser object embedded in a software product such as the browser within WinAmp, an RSS reader, or an email client. The code itself is usually written in HTML/JavaScript, but may also extend to VBScript, ActiveX, Java, Flash, or any other browser-supported technology.
When an attacker gets a user's browser to execute his/her code, the code will run within the security context (or zone) of the hosting web site. With this level of privilege, the code has the ability to read, modify and transmit any sensitive data accessible by the browser. A Cross-site Scripted user could have his/her account hijacked (cookie theft), their browser redirected to another location, or possibly shown fraudulent content delivered by the web site they are visiting. Cross-site Scripting attacks essentially compromise the trust relationship between a user and the web site. Applications utilizing browser object instances which load content from the file system may execute code under the local machine zone allowing for system compromise.

There are three types of Cross-site Scripting attacks: non-persistent, persistent and DOM-based.
Non-persistent attacks and DOM-based attacks require a user to either visit a specially crafted link laced with malicious code, or visit a malicious web page containing a web form, which when posted to the vulnerable site, will mount the attack. Using a malicious form will oftentimes take place when the vulnerable resource only accepts HTTP POST requests. In such a case, the form can be submitted automatically, without the victim's knowledge (e.g. by using JavaScript). Upon clicking on the malicious link or submitting the malicious form, the XSS payload will get echoed back and will get interpreted by the user's browser and execute. Another technique to send almost arbitrary requests (GET and POST) is by using an embedded client, such as Adobe Flash.
Persistent attacks occur when the malicious code is submitted to a web site where it's stored for a period of time. Examples of an attacker's favorite targets often include message board posts, web mail messages, and web chat software. The unsuspecting user is not required to interact with any additional site/link (e.g. an attacker site or a malicious link sent via email), just simply view the web page containing the code.</desc>
	<solution>フェーズ： アーキテクチャと設計
同脆弱性を引き起こさせない、あるいは容易に回避可能な精査されたライブラリ、あるいはフレームワークを使用してください。
Examples of libraries and frameworks that make it easier to generate properly encoded output include Microsoft's Anti-XSS library, the OWASP ESAPI Encoding module, and Apache Wicket.

Phases: Implementation; Architecture and Design
Understand the context in which your data will be used and the encoding that will be expected. This is especially important when transmitting data between different components, or when generating outputs that can contain multiple encodings at the same time, such as web pages or multi-part mail messages. Study all expected communication protocols and data representations to determine the required encoding strategies.
For any data that will be output to another web page, especially any data that was received from external inputs, use the appropriate encoding on all non-alphanumeric characters.
Consult the XSS Prevention Cheat Sheet for more details on the types of encoding and escaping that are needed.

Phase: Architecture and Design
For any security checks that are performed on the client side, ensure that these checks are duplicated on the server side, in order to avoid CWE-602. Attackers can bypass the client-side checks by modifying values after the checks have been performed, or by changing the client to remove the client-side checks entirely. Then, these modified values would be submitted to the server.

If available, use structured mechanisms that automatically enforce the separation between data and code. These mechanisms may be able to provide the relevant quoting, encoding, and validation automatically, instead of relying on the developer to provide this capability at every point where output is generated.

Phase: Implementation
For every web page that is generated, use and specify a character encoding such as ISO-8859-1 or UTF-8. When an encoding is not specified, the web browser may choose a different encoding by guessing which encoding is actually being used by the web page. This can cause the web browser to treat certain sequences as special, opening up the client to subtle XSS attacks. See CWE-116 for more mitigations related to encoding/escaping.

To help mitigate XSS attacks against the user's session cookie, set the session cookie to be HttpOnly. In browsers that support the HttpOnly feature (such as more recent versions of Internet Explorer and Firefox), this attribute can prevent the user's session cookie from being accessible to malicious client-side scripts that use document.cookie. This is not a complete solution, since HttpOnly is not supported by all browsers. More importantly, XMLHTTPRequest and other powerful browser technologies provide read access to HTTP headers, including the Set-Cookie header in which the HttpOnly flag is set.

Assume all input is malicious. Use an "accept known good" input validation strategy, i.e., use a whitelist of acceptable inputs that strictly conform to specifications. Reject any input that does not strictly conform to specifications, or transform it into something that does. Do not rely exclusively on looking for malicious or malformed inputs (i.e., do not rely on a blacklist). However, blacklists can be useful for detecting potential attacks or determining which inputs are so malformed that they should be rejected outright.

When performing input validation, consider all potentially relevant properties, including length, type of input, the full range of acceptable values, missing or extra inputs, syntax, consistency across related fields, and conformance to business rules. As an example of business rule logic, "boat" may be syntactically valid because it only contains alphanumeric characters, but it is not valid if you are expecting colors such as "red" or "blue."

Ensure that you perform input validation at well-defined interfaces within the application. This will help protect the application even if a component is reused or moved elsewhere.
	</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Cross-Site-Scripting</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/79.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_8>

<vuln_items>wasc_9</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_9>
	<alert>クロスサイト リクエスト フォージェリー(CSRF)</alert>
	<desc>A cross-site request forgery is an attack that involves forcing a victim to send an HTTP request to a target destination without their knowledge or intent in order to perform an action as the victim. The underlying cause is application functionality using predictable URL/form actions in a repeatable way. The nature of the attack is that CSRF exploits the trust that a web site has for a user. By contrast, cross-site scripting (XSS) exploits the trust that a user has for a web site. Like XSS, CSRF attacks are not necessarily cross-site, but they can be. Cross-site request forgery is also known as CSRF, XSRF, one-click attack, session riding, confused deputy, and sea surf.

CSRF attacks are effective in a number of situations, including:
    * The victim has an active session on the target site.
    * The victim is authenticated via HTTP auth on the target site.
    * The victim is on the same local network as the target site.

CSRF has primarily been used to perform an action against a target site using the victim's privileges, but recent techniques have been discovered to disclose information by gaining access to the response. The risk of information disclosure is dramatically increased when the target site is vulnerable to XSS, because XSS can be used as a platform for CSRF, allowing the attack to operate within the bounds of the same-origin policy.</desc>
	<solution>フェーズ： アーキテクチャと設計
同脆弱性を引き起こさせない、あるいは容易に回避可能な精査されたライブラリ、あるいはフレームワークを使用してください。
たとえば、OWASP CSRFGuard などのアンチCSRFパッケージを使用します。

Phase: Implementation
Ensure that your application is free of cross-site scripting issues, because most CSRF defenses can be bypassed using attacker-controlled script.

Phase: Architecture and Design
Generate a unique nonce for each form, place the nonce into the form, and verify the nonce upon receipt of the form. Be sure that the nonce is not predictable (CWE-330).
Note that this can be bypassed using XSS.

Identify especially dangerous operations. When the user performs a dangerous operation, send a separate confirmation request to ensure that the user intended to perform that operation.
Note that this can be bypassed using XSS.

Use the ESAPI Session Management control.
This control includes a component for CSRF.

Do not use the GET method for any request that triggers a state change.

Phase: Implementation
Check the HTTP Referer header to see if the request originated from an expected page. This could break legitimate functionality, because users or proxies may have disabled sending the Referer for privacy reasons.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Cross-Site-Request-Forgery</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/352.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_9>

<vuln_items>wasc_10</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_10>
	<alert>DoS(サービス運用妨害)</alert>
	<desc>Denial of Service (DoS) is an attack technique with the intent of preventing a web site from serving normal user activity. DoS attacks, which are easily normally applied to the network layer, are also possible at the application layer. These malicious attacks can succeed by starving a system of critical resources, vulnerability exploit, or abuse of functionality.

Many times DoS attacks will attempt to consume all of a web site's available system resources such as: CPU, memory, disk space etc. When any one of these critical resources reach full utilization, the web site will normally be inaccessible.

As today's web application environments include a web server, database server and an authentication server, DoS at the application layer may target each of these independent components. Unlike DoS at the network layer, where a large number of connection attempts are required, DoS at the application layer is a much simpler task to perform.</desc>
	<solution>Phase: Architecture and Design

Design throttling mechanisms into the system architecture. The best protection is to limit the amount of resources that an unauthorized user can cause to be expended. A strong authentication and access control model will help prevent such attacks from occurring in the first place. The login application should be protected against DoS attacks as much as possible. Limiting the database access, perhaps by caching result sets, can help minimize the resources expended. To further limit the potential for a DoS attack, consider tracking the rate of requests received from users and blocking requests that exceed a defined rate threshold.

Mitigation of resource exhaustion attacks requires that the target system either:
      recognizes the attack and denies that user further access for a given amount of time, or
      uniformly throttles all requests in order to make it more difficult to consume resources more quickly than they can again be freed. 

The first of these solutions is an issue in itself though, since it may allow attackers to prevent the use of the system by a particular valid user. If the attacker impersonates the valid user, he may be able to prevent the user from accessing the server in question.

The second solution is simply difficult to effectively institute -- and even when properly done, it does not provide a full solution. It simply makes the attack require more resources on the part of the attacker.

Ensure that protocols have specific limits of scale placed on them.

Phase: Implementation
Ensure that all failures in resource allocation place the system into a safe posture.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Denial-of-Service</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/400.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_10>

<vuln_items>wasc_11a</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_11a>
	<alert>総当り攻撃(ログイン情報)</alert>
	<desc>総当たり攻撃（ブルートフォースアタック）は利用可能な大量の数の値を自動化されたプロセスを使って試すことにより、不明な値を突き止める方法です。 The attack takes advantage of the fact that the entropy of the values is smaller than perceived. For example, while an 8 character alphanumeric password can have 2.8 trillion possible values, many people will select their passwords from a much smaller subset consisting of common words and terms.

The most common type of a brute force attack in web applications is an attack against log-in credentials. Since users need to remember passwords, they often select easy to memorize words or phrases as passwords, making a brute force attack using a dictionary useful. Such an attack attempting to log-in to a system using a large list of words and phrases as potential passwords is often called a "word list attack" or a "dictionary attack". Attempted passwords may also include variations of words common to passwords such as those generated by replacing "o" with "0" and "i" with "1" as well as personal information including family member names, birth dates and phone numbers.
	</desc>
	<solution>後日発表</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Brute-Force</reference>
	<reference>後日発表</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_11a>

<vuln_items>wasc_11b</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_11b>
	<alert>総当り攻撃(セッション識別子)</alert>
	<desc>総当たり攻撃（ブルートフォースアタック）は利用可能な大量の数の値を自動化されたプロセスを使って試すことにより、不明な値を突き止める方法です。 The attack takes advantage of the fact that the entropy of the values is smaller than perceived. For example, while an 8 character alphanumeric password can have 2.8 trillion possible values, many people will select their passwords from a much smaller subset consisting of common words and terms.

Since HTTP is a stateless protocol, in order to maintain state web applications need to ensure that a session identifier is sent by the browser with each request. The session identifier is most commonly stored in an HTTP cookie or URL. Using a brute force attack, an attacker can guess the session identifier of another user. This can lead to the attacker impersonating the user, retrieving personal information and performing actions on behalf of the user.
	</desc>
	<solution>後日発表</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Brute-Force</reference>
	<reference>後日発表</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_11b>

<vuln_items>wasc_11c</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_11c>
	<alert>総当り攻撃(ディレクトリ/ファイル)</alert>
	<desc>総当たり攻撃（ブルートフォースアタック）は利用可能な大量の数の値を自動化されたプロセスを使って試すことにより、不明な値を突き止める方法です。 The attack takes advantage of the fact that the entropy of the values is smaller than perceived. For example, while an 8 character alphanumeric password can have 2.8 trillion possible values, many people will select their passwords from a much smaller subset consisting of common words and terms.

When files reside in directories that are served by the web server but are not linked anywhere, accessing those files requires knowing their file name. In some cases those files have been left by mistake: for example a backup file automatically created when editing a file or leftovers from an older version of the web application. In other cases files are intentionally left unlinked as a "security by obscurity" mechanism allowing only people who know the file names to access them.

A brute force attack tries to locate the unlinked file by trying to access a large number of files. The list of attempted file names might be taken from a list of known potential files or based on variants of the visible files on the web site. More information on brute forcing directories and files can be found in the associated vulnerability, predictable resource location.
	</desc>
	<solution>後日発表</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Brute-Force</reference>
	<reference>後日発表</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_11c>

<vuln_items>wasc_11d</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_11d>
	<alert>総当り攻撃(クレジットカード情報)</alert>
	<desc>総当たり攻撃（ブルートフォースアタック）は利用可能な大量の数の値を自動化されたプロセスを使って試すことにより、不明な値を突き止める方法です。 The attack takes advantage of the fact that the entropy of the values is smaller than perceived. For example, while an 8 character alphanumeric password can have 2.8 trillion possible values, many people will select their passwords from a much smaller subset consisting of common words and terms.

Shopping online with stolen credit cards usually requires information in addition to the credit card number, most often the CVV/SCS and/or expiration date. A fraudster may hold a stolen credit card number without the additional information. For example the CVV/CSC is not imprinted on the card or stored on the magnetic stripe so it cannot be collected by mechanical or magnetic credit card swiping devices.

In order to fill in the missing information the hacker can guess the missing information using a brute force technique, trying all possible values.
    * Guessing CVV/CSC requires only 1000 or 10000 attempts as the number is only 3 or 4 digits, depending on the card type.
    * Guessing an expiration date requires only several dozen attempts.
	</desc>
	<solution>後日発表</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Brute-Force</reference>
	<reference>後日発表</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_11d>

<vuln_items>wasc_12</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_12>
	<alert>Content Spoofing</alert>
	<desc>Content Spoofing is an attack technique that allows an attacker to inject a malicious payload that is later misrepresented as legitimate content of a web application.
 
Text Only Content Spoofing
A common approach to dynamically build pages involves passing the body or portions thereof into the page via a query string value. This approach is common on error pages, or sites providing story or news entries. The content specified in this parameter is later reflected into the page to provide the content for the page.
 
Markup Reflected Content Spoofing
Some web pages are served using dynamically built HTML content sources. For example, the source location of a frame <frame src="http://foo.example/file.html"/>) could be specified by a URL parameter value. (http://foo.example/page?frame_src=http://foo.example/file.html). An attacker may be able to replace the "frame_src" parameter value with "frame_src=http://attacker.example/spoof.html". Unlike redirectors, when the resulting web page is served the browser location bar visibly remains under the user expected domain (foo.example), but the foreign data (attacker.example) is shrouded by legitimate content.

Specially crafted links can be sent to a user via e-mail, instant messages, left on bulletin board postings, or forced upon users by a Cross-site Scripting attack. If an attacker gets a user to visit a web page designated by their malicious URL, the user will believe he is viewing authentic content from one location when he is not. Users will implicitly trust the spoofed content since the browser location bar displays http://foo.example, when in fact the underlying HTML frame is referencing http://attacker.example.

This attack exploits the trust relationship established between the user and the web site. The technique has been used to create fake web pages including login forms, defacements, false press releases, etc.
	</desc>
	<solution>後日発表</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Content-Spoofing</reference>
	<reference>後日発表</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_12>

<vuln_items>wasc_13</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_13>
	<alert>情報漏洩</alert>
	<desc>Information Leakage is an application weakness where an application reveals sensitive data, such as technical details of the web application, environment, or user-specific data. Sensitive data may be used by an attacker to exploit the target web application, its hosting network, or its users. Therefore, leakage of sensitive data should be limited or prevented whenever possible. Information Leakage, in its most common form, is the result of one or more of the following conditions: A failure to scrub out HTML/Script comments containing sensitive information, improper application or server configurations, or differences in page responses for valid versus invalid data.

Failure to scrub HTML/Script comments prior to a push to the production environment can result in the leak of sensitive, contextual, information such as server directory structure, SQL query structure, and internal network information. Often a developer will leave comments within the HTML and/or script code to help facilitate the debugging or integration process during the pre-production phase. Although there is no harm in allowing developers to include inline comments within the content they develop, these comments should all be removed prior to the content's public release.

Software version numbers and verbose error messages (such as ASP.NET version numbers) are examples of improper server configurations. This information is useful to an attacker by providing detailed insight as to the framework, languages, or pre-built functions being utilized by a web application. Most default server configurations provide software version numbers and verbose error messages for debugging and troubleshooting purposes. Configuration changes can be made to disable these features, preventing the display of this information.

Pages that provide different responses based on the validity of the data can also lead to Information Leakage; specifically when data deemed confidential is being revealed as a result of the web application's design. Examples of sensitive data includes (but is not limited to): account numbers, user identifiers (Drivers license number, Passport number, Social Security Numbers, etc.) and user-specific information (passwords, sessions, addresses). Information Leakage in this context deals with exposure of key user data deemed confidential, or secret, that should not be exposed in plain view, even to the user. Credit card numbers and other heavily regulated information are prime examples of user data that needs to be further protected from exposure or leakage even with proper encryption and access controls already in place.</desc>
	<solution>Compartmentalize your system to have "safe" areas where trust boundaries can be unambiguously drawn. Do not allow sensitive data to go outside of the trust boundary and always be careful when interfacing with a compartment outside of the safe area.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Information-Leakage</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/200.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_13>

<vuln_items>wasc_14</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_14>
	<alert>サーバーの設定ミス</alert>
	<desc>Server Misconfiguration attacks exploit configuration weaknesses found in web servers and application servers. Many servers come with unnecessary default and sample files, including applications, configuration files, scripts, and web pages. They may also have unnecessary services enabled, such as content management and remote administration functionality. Debugging functions may be enabled or administrative functions may be accessible to anonymous users. These features may provide a means for a hacker to bypass authentication methods and gain access to sensitive information, perhaps with elevated privileges.

Servers may include well-known default accounts and passwords. Failure to fully lock down or harden the server may leave improperly set file and directory permissions. Misconfigured SSL certificates and encryption settings, the use of default certificates, and improper authentication implementation with external systems may compromise the confidentiality of information.

Verbose and informative error messages may result in data leakage, and the information revealed could be used to formulate the next level of attack. Incorrect configurations in the server software may permit directory indexing and path traversal attacks.</desc>
	<solution>後日発表</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Server-Misconfiguration</reference>
	<reference></reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_14>

<vuln_items>wasc_15</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_15>
	<alert>アプリケーションの設定ミス</alert>
	<desc>Application Misconfiguration attacks exploit configuration weaknesses found in web applications. Many applications come with unnecessary and unsafe features, such as debug and QA features, enabled by default. These features may provide a means for a hacker to bypass authentication methods and gain access to sensitive information, perhaps with elevated privileges.

Likewise, default installations may include well-known usernames and passwords, hard-coded backdoor accounts, special access mechanisms, and incorrect permissions set for files accessible through web servers. Default samples may be accessible in production environments. Application-based configuration files that are not properly locked down may reveal clear text connection strings to the database, and default settings in configuration files may not have been set with security in mind. All of these misconfigurations may lead to unauthorized access to sensitive information.</desc>
	<solution>後日発表</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Application-Misconfiguration</reference>
	<reference></reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_15>

<vuln_items>wasc_16</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_16>
	<alert>ディレクトリのインデックシング</alert>
	<desc>Automatic directory listing/indexing is a web server function that lists all of the files within a requested directory if the normal base file (index.html/home.html/default.htm/default.asp/default.aspx/index.php) is not present. When a user requests the main page of a web site, they normally type in a URL such as: http://www.example.com/directory1/ - using the domain name and excluding a specific file. The web server processes this request and searches the document root directory for the default file name and sends this page to the client. If this page is not present, the web server will dynamically issue a directory listing and send the output to the client. Essentially, this is equivalent to issuing an "ls" (Unix) or "dir" (Windows) command within this directory and showing the results in HTML form. From an attack and countermeasure perspective, it is important to realize that unintended directory listings may be possible due to software vulnerabilities (discussed in the example section below) combined with a specific web request.</desc>
	<solution>Recommendations include restricting access to important directories or files by adopting a need to know requirement for both the document and server root, and turning off features such as Automatic Directory Listings that could expose private files and provide information that could be utilized by an attacker when formulating or conducting an attack.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Directory-Indexing</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/548.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_16>

<vuln_items>wasc_17</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_17>
	<alert>Improper Filesystem Permissions</alert>
	<desc>Improper filesystem permissions are a threat to the confidentiality, integrity and availability of a web application. The problem arises when incorrect filesystem permissions are set on files, folders, and symbolic links. When improper permissions are set, an attacker may be able to access restricted files or directories and modify or delete their contents. For example, if an anonymous user account has write permission to a file, then an attacker may be able to modify the contents of the file influencing the web application in undesirable ways. An attacker may also exploit improper symlinks to escalate their privileges and/or access unauthorized files; for example, a symlink that points to a directory outside of the web root.</desc>
	<solution>Very carefully manage the setting, management and handling of permissions. Explicitly manage trust zones in the software.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Improper-Filesystem-Permissions</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/280.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_17>

<vuln_items>wasc_18</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_18>
	<alert>Credential and Session Prediction</alert>
	<desc>Credential/Session Prediction is a method of hijacking or impersonating a web site user. Deducing or guessing the unique value that identifies a particular session or user accomplishes the attack. Also known as Session Hijacking, the consequences could allow attackers the ability to issue web site requests with the compromised user's privileges.

Many web sites are designed to authenticate and track a user when communication is first established. To do this, users must prove their identity to the web site, typically by supplying a username/password (credentials) combination. Rather than passing these confidential credentials back and forth with each transaction, web sites will generate a unique "session ID" to identify the user session as authenticated. Subsequent communication between the user and the web site is tagged with the session ID as "proof" of the authenticated session. If an attacker is able predict or guess the session ID of another user, fraudulent activity is possible.</desc>
	<solution>後日発表</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Credential-and-Session-Prediction</reference>
	<reference></reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_18>

<vuln_items>wasc_19</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_19>
	<alert>SQL インジェクション</alert>
	<desc>SQL Injection is an attack technique used to exploit applications that construct SQL statements from user-supplied input. When successful, the attacker is able to change the logic of SQL statements executed against the database.

Structured Query Language (SQL) is a specialized programming language for sending queries to databases. The SQL programming language is both an ANSI and an ISO standard, though many database products supporting SQL do so with proprietary extensions to the standard language. Applications often use user-supplied data to create SQL statements. If an application fails to properly construct SQL statements it is possible for an attacker to alter the statement structure and execute unplanned and potentially hostile commands. When such commands are executed, they do so under the context of the user specified by the application executing the statement. This capability allows attackers to gain control of all database resources accessible by that user, up to and including the ability to execute commands on the hosting system.</desc>
	<solution>フェーズ： アーキテクチャと設計
同脆弱性を引き起こさせない、あるいは容易に回避可能な精査されたライブラリ、あるいはフレームワークを使用してください。
For example, consider using persistence layers such as Hibernate or Enterprise Java Beans, which can provide significant protection against SQL injection if used properly.

If available, use structured mechanisms that automatically enforce the separation between data and code. These mechanisms may be able to provide the relevant quoting, encoding, and validation automatically, instead of relying on the developer to provide this capability at every point where output is generated.

Process SQL queries using prepared statements, parameterized queries, or stored procedures. These features should accept parameters or variables and support strong typing. Do not dynamically construct and execute query strings within these features using "exec" or similar functionality, since you may re-introduce the possibility of SQL injection.

Run your code using the lowest privileges that are required to accomplish the necessary tasks. If possible, create isolated accounts with limited privileges that are only used for a single task. That way, a successful attack will not immediately give the attacker access to the rest of the software or its environment. For example, database applications rarely need to run as the database administrator, especially in day-to-day operations.

Specifically, follow the principle of least privilege when creating user accounts to a SQL database. The database users should only have the minimum privileges necessary to use their account. If the requirements of the system indicate that a user can read and modify their own data, then limit their privileges so they cannot read/write others' data. Use the strictest permissions possible on all database objects, such as execute-only for stored procedures.

Phase: Implementation
If you need to use dynamically-generated query strings or commands in spite of the risk, properly quote arguments and escape any special characters within those arguments. The most conservative approach is to escape or filter all characters that do not pass an extremely strict whitelist (such as everything that is not alphanumeric or white space). If some special characters are still needed, such as white space, wrap each argument in quotes after the escaping/filtering step. Be careful of argument injection (CWE-88).

Instead of building your own implementation, such features may be available in the database or programming language. For example, the Oracle DBMS ASSERT package can check or enforce that parameters have certain properties that make them less vulnerable to SQL injection. For MySQL, the mysql real escape string() API function is available in both C and PHP.

Assume all input is malicious. Use an "accept known good" input validation strategy, i.e., use a whitelist of acceptable inputs that strictly conform to specifications. Reject any input that does not strictly conform to specifications, or transform it into something that does. Do not rely exclusively on looking for malicious or malformed inputs (i.e., do not rely on a blacklist). However, blacklists can be useful for detecting potential attacks or determining which inputs are so malformed that they should be rejected outright.

When performing input validation, consider all potentially relevant properties, including length, type of input, the full range of acceptable values, missing or extra inputs, syntax, consistency across related fields, and conformance to business rules. As an example of business rule logic, "boat" may be syntactically valid because it only contains alphanumeric characters, but it is not valid if you are expecting colors such as "red" or "blue."

When constructing SQL query strings, use stringent whitelists that limit the character set based on the expected value of the parameter in the request. This will indirectly limit the scope of an attack, but this technique is less important than proper output encoding and escaping.

Note that proper output encoding, escaping, and quoting is the most effective solution for preventing SQL injection, although input validation may provide some defense-in-depth. This is because it effectively limits what will appear in output. Input validation will not always prevent SQL injection, especially if you are required to support free-form text fields that could contain arbitrary characters. For example, the name "O'Reilly" would likely pass the validation step, since it is a common last name in the English language. However, it cannot be directly inserted into the database because it contains the "'" apostrophe character, which would need to be escaped or otherwise handled. In this case, stripping the apostrophe might reduce the risk of SQL injection, but it would produce incorrect behavior because the wrong name would be recorded.

When feasible, it may be safest to disallow meta-characters entirely, instead of escaping them. This will provide some defense in depth. After the data is entered into the database, later processes may neglect to escape meta-characters before use, and you may not have control over those processes.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/SQL-Injection</reference>
	<reference></reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_19>

<vuln_items>wasc_20</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_20>
	<alert>Improper Input Handling</alert>
	<desc>Improper input handling is one of the most common weaknesses identified across applications today. Poorly handled input is a leading cause behind critical vulnerabilities that exist in systems and applications.
	
Generally, the term input handing is used to describe functions like validation, sanitization, filtering, encoding and/or decoding of input data. Applications receive input from various sources including human users, software agents (browsers), and network/peripheral devices to name a few. In the case of web applications, input can be transferred in various formats (name value pairs, JSON, SOAP, etc...) and obtained via URL query strings, POST data, HTTP headers, Cookies, etc... Non-web application input can be obtained via application variables, environment variables, the registry, configuration files, etc... Regardless of the data format or source/location of the input, all input should be considered untrusted and potentially malicious. Applications which process untrusted input may become vulnerable to attacks such as Buffer Overflows, SQL Injection, OS Commanding, Denial of Service just to name a few.

One of the key aspects of input handling is validating that the input satisfies a certain criteria. For proper validation, it is important to identify the form and type of data that is acceptable and expected by the application. Defining an expected format and usage of each instance of untrusted input is required to accurately define restrictions. 

Validation can include checks for type safety and correct syntax. String input can be checked for length (min and max number of characters) and character set validation while numeric input types like integers and decimals can be validated against acceptable upper and lower bound of values. When combining input from multiple sources, validation should be performed during concatenation and not just against the individual data elements. This practice helps avoid situations where input validation may succeed when performed on individual data items but fails when done on a combined set from all the sources.</desc>
	<solution>Phase: Architecture and Design

Use an input validation framework such as Struts or the OWASP ESAPI Validation API.

Understand all the potential areas where untrusted inputs can enter your software: parameters or arguments, cookies, anything read from the network, environment variables, reverse DNS lookups, query results, request headers, URL components, e-mail, files, databases, and any external systems that provide data to the application. Remember that such inputs may be obtained indirectly through API calls.

For any security checks that are performed on the client side, ensure that these checks are duplicated on the server side. Attackers can bypass the client-side checks by modifying values after the checks have been performed, or by changing the client to remove the client-side checks entirely. Then, these modified values would be submitted to the server.

Even though client-side checks provide minimal benefits with respect to server-side security, they are still useful. First, they can support intrusion detection. If the server receives input that should have been rejected by the client, then it may be an indication of an attack. Second, client-side error-checking can provide helpful feedback to the user about the expectations for valid input. Third, there may be a reduction in server-side processing time for accidental input errors, although this is typically a small savings.

Do not rely exclusively on blacklist validation to detect malicious input or to encode output. There are too many ways to encode the same character, so you're likely to miss some variants.

When your application combines data from multiple sources, perform the validation after the sources have been combined. The individual data elements may pass the validation step but violate the intended restrictions after they have been combined.

Assume all input is malicious. Use an "accept known good" input validation strategy, i.e., use a whitelist of acceptable inputs that strictly conform to specifications. Reject any input that does not strictly conform to specifications, or transform it into something that does. Do not rely exclusively on looking for malicious or malformed inputs (i.e., do not rely on a blacklist). However, blacklists can be useful for detecting potential attacks or determining which inputs are so malformed that they should be rejected outright.

When performing input validation, consider all potentially relevant properties, including length, type of input, the full range of acceptable values, missing or extra inputs, syntax, consistency across related fields, and conformance to business rules. As an example of business rule logic, "boat" may be syntactically valid because it only contains alphanumeric characters, but it is not valid if you are expecting colors such as "red" or "blue."

Phase: Implementation

Be especially careful to validate your input when you invoke code that crosses language boundaries, such as from an interpreted language to native code. This could create an unexpected interaction between the language boundaries. Ensure that you are not violating any of the expectations of the language with which you are interfacing. For example, even though Java may not be susceptible to buffer overflows, providing a large argument in a call to native code might trigger an overflow.

Directly convert your input type into the expected data type, such as using a conversion function that translates a string into a number. After converting to the expected data type, ensure that the input's values fall within the expected range of allowable values and that multi-field consistencies are maintained.

Inputs should be decoded and canonicalized to the application's current internal representation before being validated. Make sure that your application does not inadvertently decode the same input twice. Such errors could be used to bypass whitelist schemes by introducing dangerous inputs after they have been checked. Use libraries such as the OWASP ESAPI Canonicalization control.

Consider performing repeated canonicalization until your input does not change any more. This will avoid double-decoding and similar scenarios, but it might inadvertently modify inputs that are allowed to contain properly-encoded dangerous content.

When exchanging data between components, ensure that both components are using the same character encoding. Ensure that the proper encoding is applied at each interface. Explicitly set the encoding you are using whenever the protocol allows you to do so.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Improper-Input-Handling</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/89.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_20>

<vuln_items>wasc_21</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_21>
	<alert>Insufficient Anti automation</alert>
	<desc>Insufficient Anti-automation occurs when a web application permits an attacker to automate a process that was originally designed to be performed only in a manual fashion, i.e. by a human web user.

Web application functionality that is often a target for automation attacks may include:
    * Application login forms – attackers may automate brute force login requests in an attempt to guess user credentials
    * Service registration forms – attackers may automatically create thousands of new accounts
    * Email forms – attackers may exploit email forms as spam relays or for flooding a certain user’s mailbox
    * Account maintenance – attackers may perform mass DoS against an application, by flooding it with numerous requests to disable or delete user accounts
    * Account information forms – attackers may perform mass attempts to harvest user personal information from a web application
    * Comment forms / Content Submission forms – these may be used for spamming blogs, web forums and web bulletin boards by automatically submitting contents such as spam or even web-based malware
    * Forms tied to SQL database queries - these may be exploited in order to perform a denial of service attack against the application. The attack is performed by sending numerous heavy SQL queries in a short period of time, hence denying real users from service.
    * eShopping / eCommerce - eShopping and eCommerce applications that do not enforce human-only buyers, can be exploited in order to buy preferred items in large amounts, such as sporting events tickets. These are later sold by scalpers for higher prices.
    * Online polls - polls and other types of online voting systems can be automatically subverted in favor of a certain choice.
    * Web-based SMS message sending - attackers may exploit SMS message sending systems in order to spam mobile phone users
	</desc>
	<solution>後日発表</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Insufficient+Anti-automation</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/116.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_21>

<vuln_items>wasc_22</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_22>
	<alert>Improper Output Handling</alert>
	<desc>Output handling refers to how an application generates outgoing data.  If an application has improper output handling, the output data may be consumed leading to vulnerabilities and actions never intended by the application developer.  In many cases, this unintended interpretation is classified as one or more forms of critical application vulnerabilities.

Any location where data leaves an application boundary may be subject to improper output handling.  Application boundaries exist where data leaves one context and enters another.  This includes applications passing data to other applications via web services, sockets, command line, environmental variables, etc...  It also includes passing data between tiers within an application architecture, such as a database, directory server, HTML/JavaScript interpreter (browser), or operating system.  More detail on where improper output handling can occur can be found in the section below titled "Common Data Output Locations”.

Improper output handling may take various forms within an application.  These forms can be categorized into: protocol errors, application errors and data consumer related errors.  Protocol errors include missing or improper output encoding or escaping and outputting of invalid data.  Application errors include logic errors such as outputting incorrect data or passing on malicious content unfiltered.  If the application does not properly distinguish legitimate content from illegitimate, or does not work around known vulnerabilities in the data consumer, it may result in data-consumer abuse caused from improper output handling.

An application that does not provide data in the correct context may allow an attacker to abuse the data consumer.  This can lead to specific threats referenced within the WASC Threat Classification, including Content Spoofing, Cross-Site Scripting, HTTP Response Splitting, HTTP Response Smuggling, LDAP Injection, OS Commanding, Routing Detour, Soap Array Abuse, URL Redirector, XML Injection, XQuery Injection, XPath Injection, Mail Command Injection, Null Injection and SQL Injection.

Proper output handling prevents the unexpected or unintended interpretation of data by the consumer.  To achieve this objective, developers must understand the application's data model, how the data will be consumed by other portions of the application, and how it will ultimately be presented to the user.  Techniques for ensuring the proper handling of output include but are not limited to the filtering and sanitization of data (more detail on output sanitization and filtering can be found in appropriately titled sections below).  However, inconsistent use of selected output handling techniques may actually increase the risk of improper output handling if output data is overlooked or left untreated.  To ensure "defense in depth" developers must assume that all data within an application is untrusted when choosing appropriate output handling strategies.

While proper output handling may take many different forms, an application cannot be secure unless it protects against unintended interpretations by the data consumer. This core requirement is essential for an application to securely handle output operations.</desc>
	<solution>Use a vetted library or framework that does not allow this weakness to occur or provides constructs that make this weakness easier to avoid.

For example, consider using the ESAPI Encoding control or a similar tool, library, or framework. These will help the programmer encode outputs in a manner less prone to error.

Alternately, use built-in functions, but consider using wrappers in case those functions are discovered to have a vulnerability.

If available, use structured mechanisms that automatically enforce the separation between data and code. These mechanisms may be able to provide the relevant quoting, encoding, and validation automatically, instead of relying on the developer to provide this capability at every point where output is generated.

For example, stored procedures can enforce database query structure and reduce the likelihood of SQL injection.

Understand the context in which your data will be used and the encoding that will be expected. This is especially important when transmitting data between different components, or when generating outputs that can contain multiple encodings at the same time, such as web pages or multi-part mail messages. Study all expected communication protocols and data representations to determine the required encoding strategies.

In some cases, input validation may be an important strategy when output encoding is not a complete solution. For example, you may be providing the same output that will be processed by multiple consumers that use different encodings or representations. In other cases, you may be required to allow user-supplied input to contain control information, such as limited HTML tags that support formatting in a wiki or bulletin board. When this type of requirement must be met, use an extremely strict whitelist to limit which control sequences can be used. Verify that the resulting syntactic structure is what you expect. Use your normal encoding methods for the remainder of the input.

Use input validation as a defense-in-depth measure to reduce the likelihood of output encoding errors (see CWE-20).

When exchanging data between components, ensure that both components are using the same character encoding. Ensure that the proper encoding is applied at each interface. Explicitly set the encoding you are using whenever the protocol allows you to do so.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Improper-Output-Handling</reference>
	<reference></reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_22>

<vuln_items>wasc_23</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_23>
	<alert>XML インジェクション</alert>
	<desc>XML Injection is an attack technique used to manipulate or compromise the logic of an XML application or service. The injection of unintended XML content and/or structures into an XML message can alter the intend logic of the application. Further, XML injection can cause the insertion of malicious content into the resulting message/document.</desc>
	<solution>後日発表</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/XML-Injection</reference>
	<reference></reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_23>

<vuln_items>wasc_24</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_24>
	<alert>HTTPリクエストの分割</alert>
	<desc>HTTP Request Splitting is an attack that enables forcing the browser to send arbitrary HTTP requests, inflicting XSS and poisoning the browser's cache. The essence of the attack is the ability of the attacker, once the victim (browser) is forced to load the attacker's malicious HTML page, to manipulate one of the browser's functions to send 2 HTTP requests instead of one HTTP request. Two such mechanisms have been exploited to date: the XmlHttpRequest object (XHR for short) and the HTTP digest authentication mechanism. For this attack to work, the browser must use a forward HTTP proxy (not all of them "support" this attack), or the attack must be carried out against a host located on the same IP (from the browser's perspective) with the attacker's machine.</desc>
	<solution>Avoid using CRLF as a special sequence.

Appropriately filter or quote CRLF sequences in user-controlled input.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/HTTP-Request-Splitting</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/93.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_24>

<vuln_items>wasc_25</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_25>
	<alert>HTTPレスポンスの分割</alert>
	<desc>In the HTTP Response Splitting attack, there are always 3 parties (at least) involved:
    * Web server, which has a security hole enabling HTTP Response Splitting
    * Target - an entity that interacts with the web server perhaps on behalf of the attacker. Typically this is a cache server forward/reverse proxy), or a browser (possibly with a browser cache).
    * Attacker - initiates the attack

The essence of HTTP Response Splitting is the attacker's ability to send a single HTTP request that forces the web server to form an output stream, which is then interpreted by the target as two HTTP responses instead of one response, in the normal case. The first response may be partially controlled by the attacker, but this is less important. What is material is that the attacker completely controls the form of the second response from the HTTP status line to the last byte of the HTTP response body. Once this is possible, the attacker realizes the attack by sending two requests through the target. The first one invokes two responses from the web server, and the second request would typically be to some "innocent" resource on the web server. However, the second request would be matched, by the target, to the second HTTP response, which is fully controlled by the attacker. The attacker, therefore, tricks the target into believing that a particular resource on the web server (designated by the second request) is the server's HTTP response (server content), while it is in fact some data, which is forged by the attacker through the web server - this is the second response.

HTTP Response Splitting attacks take place where the server script embeds user data in HTTP response headers. This typically happens when the script embeds user data in the redirection URL of a redirection response (HTTP status code 3xx), or when the script embeds user data in a cookie value or name when the response sets a cookie.</desc>
	<solution>Construct HTTP headers very carefully, avoiding the use of non-validated input data.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/HTTP-Response-Splitting</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/113.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_25>

<vuln_items>wasc_26</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_26>
	<alert>HTTP Request Smuggling</alert>
	<desc>HTTP Request Smuggling is an attack technique that abuses the discrepancy in parsing of non RFC compliant HTTP requests between two HTTP devices (typically a front-end proxy or HTTP-enabled firewall and a back-end web server) to smuggle a request to the second device "through" the first device. This technique enables the attacker to send one set of requests to the second device while the first device sees a different set of requests. In turn, this facilitates several possible exploitations, such as partial cache poisoning, bypassing firewall protection and XSS.</desc>
	<solution>Use a web server that employs a strict HTTP parsing procedure, such as Apache (See paper in reference).

Use only SSL communication.

Terminate the client session after each request.

Turn all pages to non-cacheable.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/HTTP-Request-Smuggling</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/444.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_26>

<vuln_items>wasc_27</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_27>
	<alert>HTTP Response Smuggling</alert>
	<desc>HTTP response smuggling is a technique to "smuggle" 2 HTTP responses from a server to a client, through an intermediary HTTP device that expects (or allows) a single response from the server.

One use for this technique is to enhance the basic HTTP response splitting technique in order to evade anti- HTTP response splitting measures. In this case, the intermediary is the anti-HTTP response splitting mechanism between the web server and the proxy server (or web browser). Another use case is to spoof responses received by the browser. In this case a malicious web site serves the browser a page that the browser will interpret as originating from a different (target) domain. HTTP response smuggling can be used to achieve this when the browser uses a proxy server to access both sites.

HTTP response smuggling makes use of HTTP request smuggling -like techniques to exploit the discrepancies between what an anti- HTTP Response Splitting mechanism (or a proxy server) would consider to be the HTTP response stream, and the response stream as parsed by a proxy server (or a browser). So, while an anti- HTTP response splitting mechanism may consider a particular response stream harmless (single HTTP response), a proxy/browser may still parse it as two HTTP responses, and hence be susceptible to all the outcomes of the original HTTP response splitting technique (in the first use case) or be susceptible to page spoofing (in the second case). For example, some anti- HTTP response splitting mechanisms in use by some application engines forbid the application from inserting a header containing CR+LF to the response. Yet an attacker can force the application to insert a header containing CRs, thereby circumventing the defense mechanism. Some proxy servers may still treat CR (only) as a header (and response) separator, and as such the combination of web server and proxy server will still be vulnerable to an attack that may poison the proxy's cache.
	</desc>
	<solution>後日発表</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/HTTP-Response-Smuggling</reference>
	<reference></reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_27>

<vuln_items>wasc_28</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_28>
	<alert>Null バイト インジェクション</alert>
	<desc>Null Byte Injection is an active exploitation technique used to bypass sanity checking filters in web infrastructure by adding URL-encoded null byte characters (i.e. %00, or 0x00 in hex) to the user-supplied data. This injection process can alter the intended logic of the application and allow malicious adversary to get unauthorized access to the system files.

Most web applications today are developed using higher-level languages such as, PHP, ASP, Perl, and Java. However, these web applications at some point require processing of high-level code at system level and this process is usually accomplished by using ‘C/C++’ functions. The diverse nature of these dependent technologies has resulted in an attack class called ‘Null Byte Injection’ or ‘Null Byte Poisoning’ attack. In C/C++, a null byte represents the string termination point or delimiter character which means to stop processing the string immediately. Bytes following the delimiter will be ignored. If the string loses its null character, the length of a string becomes unknown until memory pointer happens to meet next zero byte. This unintended ramification can cause unusual behavior and introduce vulnerabilities within the system or application scope. In similar terms, several higher-level languages treat the ‘null byte’ as a placeholder for the string length as it has no special meaning in their context. Due to this difference in interpretation, null bytes can easily be injected to manipulate the application behavior.

URLs are limited to a set of US-ASCII characters ranging from 0x20 to 0x7E (hex) or 32 to 126 (decimal). However, the aforementioned range uses several characters that are not permitted because they have special meaning within HTTP protocol context. For this reason, the URL encoding scheme was introduced to include special characters within URL using the extended ASCII character representation. In terms of “null byte”, this is represented as %00 in hexadecimal. The scope of a null byte attack starts where web applications interact with active ‘C’ routines and external APIs from the underlying OS. Thus, allowing an attacker to manipulate web resources by reading or writing files based on the application's user privileges.</desc>
	<solution>Developers should anticipate that null characters or null bytes will be injected/removed/manipulated in the input vectors of their software system. Use an appropriate combination of black lists and white lists to ensure only valid, expected and appropriate input is processed by the system.

Assume all input is malicious. Use a standard input validation mechanism to validate all input for length, type, syntax, and business rules before accepting the data to be displayed or stored. Use an "accept known good" validation strategy.

Use and specify a strong output encoding (such as ISO 8859-1 or UTF 8).

Do not rely exclusively on blacklist validation to detect malicious input or to encode output. There are too many variants to encode a character; you're likely to miss some variants.

Inputs should be decoded and canonicalized to the application's current internal representation before being validated. Make sure that your application does not decode the same input twice. Such errors could be used to bypass whitelist schemes by introducing dangerous inputs after they have been checked.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Null-Byte-Injection</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/158.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_28>

<vuln_items>wasc_29</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_29>
	<alert>LDAP インジェクション</alert>
	<desc>LDAP Injection is an attack technique used to exploit web sites that construct LDAP statements from user-supplied input.

Lightweight Directory Access Protocol (LDAP) is an open-standard protocol for both querying and manipulating X.500 directory services. The LDAP protocol runs over Internet transport protocols, such as TCP. Web applications may use user-supplied input to create custom LDAP statements for dynamic web page requests.

When a web application fails to properly sanitize user-supplied input, it is possible for an attacker to alter the construction of an LDAP statement. When an attacker is able to modify an LDAP statement, the process will run with the same permissions as the component that executed the command. (e.g. Database server, Web application server, Web server, etc.). This can cause serious security problems where the permissions grant the rights to query, modify or remove anything inside the LDAP tree. The same advanced exploitation techniques available in SQL Injection can also be similarly applied in LDAP Injection.</desc>
	<solution>Assume all input is malicious. Use an appropriate combination of black lists and white lists to neutralize LDAP syntax from user-controlled input.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/LDAP-Injection</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/90.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_29>

<vuln_items>wasc_30</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_30>
	<alert>メール コマンド インジェクション</alert>
	<desc>Mail Command Injection is an attack technique used to exploit mail servers and webmail applications that construct IMAP/SMTP statements from user-supplied input that is not properly sanitized. Depending on the type of statement taken advantage by the attacker, we meet two types of injections: IMAP and SMTP Injection. An IMAP/SMTP Injection may make it possible to access a mail server which you previously had no access to before-hand. In some cases, these internal systems do not have the same level of infrastructure security hardening applied to them as most front-end web servers. Hence, attackers may find that the mail server yields better results in terms of exploitation. On the other hand, this technique allows to evade possible restrictions that could exist at application level (CAPTCHA, maximum number of requests, etc.).</desc>
	<solution>Understand all the potential areas where untrusted inputs can enter your software: parameters or arguments, cookies, anything read from the network, environment variables, request headers as well as content, URL components, e-mail, files, databases, and any external systems that provide data to the application. Perform input validation at well-defined interfaces.

Assume all input is malicious. Use an "accept known good" input validation strategy (i.e., use a whitelist). Reject any input that does not strictly conform to specifications, or transform it into something that does. Use a blacklist to reject any unexpected inputs and detect potential attacks.

Do not rely exclusively on blacklist validation to detect malicious input or to encode output. There are too many ways to encode the same character, so you're likely to miss some variants.

Directly convert your input type into the expected data type, such as using a conversion function that translates a string into a number. After converting to the expected data type, ensure that the input's values fall within the expected range of allowable values and that multi-field consistencies are maintained.

Inputs should be decoded and canonicalized to the application's current internal representation before being validated. Make sure that your application does not inadvertently decode the same input twice . Such errors could be used to bypass whitelist schemes by introducing dangerous inputs after they have been checked. Use libraries such as the OWASP ESAPI Canonicalization control.

Consider performing repeated canonicalization until your input does not change any more. This will avoid double-decoding and similar scenarios, but it might inadvertently modify inputs that are allowed to contain properly-encoded dangerous content.

When exchanging data between components, ensure that both components are using the same character encoding. Ensure that the proper encoding is applied at each interface. Explicitly set the encoding you are using whenever the protocol allows you to do so.

When your application combines data from multiple sources, perform the validation after the sources have been combined. The individual data elements may pass the validation step but violate the intended restrictions after they have been combined.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Mail-Command-Injection</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/88.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_30>

<vuln_items>wasc_31</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_31>
	<alert>OSコマンド インジェクション</alert>
	<desc>OS Commanding is an attack technique used for unauthorized execution of operating system commands.

OS Commanding is the direct result of mixing trusted code and untrusted data. This attack is possible when an application accepts untrusted input to build operating system commands in an insecure manner involving improper data sanitization, and/or improper calling of external programs. In OS Commanding, executed commands by an attacker will run with the same privileges of the component that executed the command, (e.g. database server, web application server, web server, wrapper, application). Since the commands are executed under the privileges of the executing component an attacker can leverage this to gain access or damage parts that are otherwise unreachable (e.g. the operating system directories and files).</desc>
	<solution>If at all possible, use library calls rather than external processes to recreate the desired functionality.

Run your code in a "jail" or similar sandbox environment that enforces strict boundaries between the process and the operating system. This may effectively restrict which files can be accessed in a particular directory or which commands can be executed by your software.

OS-level examples include the Unix chroot jail, AppArmor, and SELinux. In general, managed code may provide some protection. For example, java.io.FilePermission in the Java SecurityManager allows you to specify restrictions on file operations.
This may not be a feasible solution, and it only limits the impact to the operating system; the rest of your application may still be subject to compromise.

For any data that will be used to generate a command to be executed, keep as much of that data out of external control as possible. For example, in web applications, this may require storing the command locally in the session's state instead of sending it out to the client in a hidden form field.

Use a vetted library or framework that does not allow this weakness to occur or provides constructs that make this weakness easier to avoid.

For example, consider using the ESAPI Encoding control or a similar tool, library, or framework. These will help the programmer encode outputs in a manner less prone to error.

If you need to use dynamically-generated query strings or commands in spite of the risk, properly quote arguments and escape any special characters within those arguments. The most conservative approach is to escape or filter all characters that do not pass an extremely strict whitelist (such as everything that is not alphanumeric or white space). If some special characters are still needed, such as white space, wrap each argument in quotes after the escaping/filtering step. Be careful of argument injection.

If the program to be executed allows arguments to be specified within an input file or from standard input, then consider using that mode to pass arguments instead of the command line.

If available, use structured mechanisms that automatically enforce the separation between data and code. These mechanisms may be able to provide the relevant quoting, encoding, and validation automatically, instead of relying on the developer to provide this capability at every point where output is generated.

Some languages offer multiple functions that can be used to invoke commands. Where possible, identify any function that invokes a command shell using a single string, and replace it with a function that requires individual arguments. These functions typically perform appropriate quoting and filtering of arguments. For example, in C, the system() function accepts a string that contains the entire command to be executed, whereas execl(), execve(), and others require an array of strings, one for each argument. In Windows, CreateProcess() only accepts one command at a time. In Perl, if system() is provided with an array of arguments, then it will quote each of the arguments.

Assume all input is malicious. Use an "accept known good" input validation strategy, i.e., use a whitelist of acceptable inputs that strictly conform to specifications. Reject any input that does not strictly conform to specifications, or transform it into something that does. Do not rely exclusively on looking for malicious or malformed inputs (i.e., do not rely on a blacklist). However, blacklists can be useful for detecting potential attacks or determining which inputs are so malformed that they should be rejected outright.

When performing input validation, consider all potentially relevant properties, including length, type of input, the full range of acceptable values, missing or extra inputs, syntax, consistency across related fields, and conformance to business rules. As an example of business rule logic, "boat" may be syntactically valid because it only contains alphanumeric characters, but it is not valid if you are expecting colors such as "red" or "blue."

When constructing OS command strings, use stringent whitelists that limit the character set based on the expected value of the parameter in the request. This will indirectly limit the scope of an attack, but this technique is less important than proper output encoding and escaping.

Note that proper output encoding, escaping, and quoting is the most effective solution for preventing OS command injection, although input validation may provide some defense-in-depth. This is because it effectively limits what will appear in output. Input validation will not always prevent OS command injection, especially if you are required to support free-form text fields that could contain arbitrary characters. For example, when invoking a mail program, you might need to allow the subject field to contain otherwise-dangerous inputs like ";" and ">" characters, which would need to be escaped or otherwise handled. In this case, stripping the character might reduce the risk of OS command injection, but it would produce incorrect behavior because the subject field would not be recorded as the user intended. This might seem to be a minor inconvenience, but it could be more important when the program relies on well-structured subject lines in order to pass messages to other components.

Even if you make a mistake in your validation (such as forgetting one out of 100 input fields), appropriate encoding is still likely to protect you from injection-based attacks. As long as it is not done in isolation, input validation is still a useful technique, since it may significantly reduce your attack surface, allow you to detect some attacks, and provide other security benefits that proper encoding does not address.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/OS-Commanding</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/78.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_31>

<vuln_items>wasc_32</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_32>
	<alert>Routing Detour</alert>
	<desc>The WS-Routing Protocol (WS-Routing) is a protocol for exchanging SOAP messages from an initial message sender to an ultimate receiver, typically via a set of intermediaries. The WS-Routing protocol is implemented as a SOAP extension, and is embedded in the SOAP Header. WS-Routing is often used to provide a way to direct XML traffic through complex environments and transactions by allowing interim way stations in the XML path to assign routing instructions to an XML document.

Routing Detours are a type of "Man in the Middle" attack where Intermediaries can be injected or "hijacked" to route sensitive messages to an outside location. Routing information (either in the HTTP header or in WS-Routing header) can be modified en route and traces of the routing can be removed from the header and message such that the receiving application none the wiser that a routing detour has occurred. The header and the insertion of header objects is often less protected than the message; this is due to the fact that the header is used as a catch all for metadata about the transaction such as authentication, routing, formatting, schema, canonicalization, namespaces, etc. Also, many processes may be involved in adding to/processing the header of an XML document. In many implementations the routing info can come from an external web service (using WS-Referral for example) that provides the specific routing for the transaction.

WS-Addressing is a newer standard published by the W3C to provide routing functionality to SOAP messages. One of the key differences between WS-Routing and WS-Addressing is that WS-Addressing only provides the next location in the route. While little research has been done into the susceptibility of WS-Addressing to Routing Detour Attack, at least one paper (see reference #6 below) suggests that WS-Addressing is vulnerable to Routing Detour as well.</desc>
	<solution>Always fully authenticate both ends of any communications channel.

Adhere to the principle of complete mediation.

A certificate binds an identity to a cryptographic key to authenticate a communicating party. Often, the certificate takes the encrypted form of the hash of the identity of the subject, the public key, and information such as time of issue or expiration using the issuer's private key. The certificate can be validated by deciphering the certificate with the issuer's public key. See also X.509 certificate signature chains and the PGP certification structure.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Routing-Detour</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/300.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_32>

<vuln_items>wasc_33</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_33>
	<alert>パス トラバーサル</alert>
	<desc>The Path Traversal attack technique allows an attacker access to files, directories, and commands that potentially reside outside the web document root directory. An attacker may manipulate a URL in such a way that the web site will execute or reveal the contents of arbitrary files anywhere on the web server. Any device that exposes an HTTP-based interface is potentially vulnerable to Path Traversal.

Most web sites restrict user access to a specific portion of the file-system, typically called the "web document root" or "CGI root" directory. These directories contain the files intended for user access and the executable necessary to drive web application functionality. To access files or execute commands anywhere on the file-system, Path Traversal attacks will utilize the ability of special-characters sequences.

The most basic Path Traversal attack uses the "../" special-character sequence to alter the resource location requested in the URL. Although most popular web servers will prevent this technique from escaping the web document root, alternate encodings of the "../" sequence may help bypass the security filters. These method variations include valid and invalid Unicode-encoding ("..%u2216" or "..%c0%af") of the forward slash character, backslash characters ("..\") on Windows-based servers, URL encoded characters "%2e%2e%2f"), and double URL encoding ("..%255c") of the backslash character.

Even if the web server properly restricts Path Traversal attempts in the URL path, a web application itself may still be vulnerable due to improper handling of user-supplied input. This is a common problem of web applications that use template mechanisms or load static text from files. In variations of the attack, the original URL parameter value is substituted with the file name of one of the web application's dynamic scripts. Consequently, the results can reveal source code because the file is interpreted as text instead of an executable script. These techniques often employ additional special characters such as the dot (".") to reveal the listing of the current working directory, or "%00" NULL characters in order to bypass rudimentary file extension checks.</desc>
	<solution>Assume all input is malicious. Use an "accept known good" input validation strategy, i.e., use a whitelist of acceptable inputs that strictly conform to specifications. Reject any input that does not strictly conform to specifications, or transform it into something that does. Do not rely exclusively on looking for malicious or malformed inputs (i.e., do not rely on a blacklist). However, blacklists can be useful for detecting potential attacks or determining which inputs are so malformed that they should be rejected outright.

When performing input validation, consider all potentially relevant properties, including length, type of input, the full range of acceptable values, missing or extra inputs, syntax, consistency across related fields, and conformance to business rules. As an example of business rule logic, "boat" may be syntactically valid because it only contains alphanumeric characters, but it is not valid if you are expecting colors such as "red" or "blue."

For filenames, use stringent whitelists that limit the character set to be used. If feasible, only allow a single "." character in the filename to avoid weaknesses, and exclude directory separators such as "/". Use a whitelist of allowable file extensions.

Warning: if you attempt to cleanse your data, then do so that the end result is not in the form that can be dangerous. A sanitizing mechanism can remove characters such as '.' and ';' which may be required for some exploits. An attacker can try to fool the sanitizing mechanism into "cleaning" data into a dangerous form. Suppose the attacker injects a '.' inside a filename (e.g. "sensi.tiveFile") and the sanitizing mechanism removes the character resulting in the valid filename, "sensitiveFile". If the input data are now assumed to be safe, then the file may be compromised. 

Inputs should be decoded and canonicalized to the application's current internal representation before being validated. Make sure that your application does not decode the same input twice. Such errors could be used to bypass whitelist schemes by introducing dangerous inputs after they have been checked.

Use a built-in path canonicalization function (such as realpath() in C) that produces the canonical version of the pathname, which effectively removes ".." sequences and symbolic links.

Run your code using the lowest privileges that are required to accomplish the necessary tasks. If possible, create isolated accounts with limited privileges that are only used for a single task. That way, a successful attack will not immediately give the attacker access to the rest of the software or its environment. For example, database applications rarely need to run as the database administrator, especially in day-to-day operations.

When the set of acceptable objects, such as filenames or URLs, is limited or known, create a mapping from a set of fixed input values (such as numeric IDs) to the actual filenames or URLs, and reject all other inputs.

Run your code in a "jail" or similar sandbox environment that enforces strict boundaries between the process and the operating system. This may effectively restrict which files can be accessed in a particular directory or which commands can be executed by your software.

OS-level examples include the Unix chroot jail, AppArmor, and SELinux. In general, managed code may provide some protection. For example, java.io.FilePermission in the Java SecurityManager allows you to specify restrictions on file operations.

This may not be a feasible solution, and it only limits the impact to the operating system; the rest of your application may still be subject to compromise.
</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Path-Traversal</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/22.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_33>

<vuln_items>wasc_34</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_34>
	<alert>推測可能なリソースの位置</alert>
	<desc>Predictable Resource Location is an attack technique used to uncover hidden web site content and functionality. By making educated guesses via brute forcing an attacker can guess file and directory names not intended for public viewing. Brute forcing filenames is easy because files/paths often have common naming convention and reside in standard locations. These can include temporary files, backup files, logs, administrative site sections, configuration files, demo applications, and sample files. These files may disclose sensitive information about the website, web application internals, database information, passwords, machine names, file paths to other sensitive areas, etc...

This will not only assist with identifying site surface which may lead to additional site vulnerabilities, but also may disclose valuable information to an attacker about the environment or its users. Predictable Resource Location is also known as Forced Browsing, Forceful Browsing, File Enumeration, and Directory Enumeration.</desc>
	<solution>Apply appropriate access control authorizations for each access to all restricted URLs, scripts or files.

Consider using MVC based frameworks such as Struts.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Predictable-Resource-Location</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/425.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_34>

<vuln_items>wasc_35</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_35>
	<alert>SOAP Array Abuse</alert>
	<desc>XML SOAP arrays are a common target for malicious abuse. SOAP arrays are defined as having a type of "SOAP-ENC:Array" or a type derived there from. SOAP arrays have one or more dimensions (rank) whose members are distinguished by ordinal position. An array value is represented as a series of elements reflecting the array, with members appearing in ascending ordinal sequence. For multi-dimensional arrays the dimension on the right side varies most rapidly. Each member element is named as an independent element. A web-service that expects an array can be the target of a XML DoS attack by forcing the SOAP server to build a huge array in the machine's memory, thus inflicting a DoS condition on the machine due to the memory pre-allocation.</desc>
	<solution> Perform adequate input validation against any value that influences the amount of memory that is allocated. Define an appropriate strategy for handling requests that exceed the limit, and consider supporting a configuration option so that the administrator can extend the amount of memory to be used if necessary.

Run your program using system-provided resource limits for memory. This might still cause the program to crash or exit, but the impact to the rest of the system will be minimized.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/SOAP-Array-Abuse</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/789.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_35>

<vuln_items>wasc_36</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_36>
	<alert>SSI インジェクション</alert>
	<desc>SSI Injection (Server-side Include) is a server-side exploit technique that allows an attacker to send code into a web application, which will later be executed locally by the web server. SSI Injection exploits a web application's failure to sanitize user-supplied data before they are inserted into a server-side interpreted HTML file.

Before serving an HTML web page, a web server may parse and execute Server-side Include statements before providing it to the client. In some cases (e.g. message boards, guest books, or content management systems), a web application will insert user-supplied data into the source of a web page.

If an attacker submits a Server-side Include statement, he may have the ability to execute arbitrary operating system commands, or include a restricted file's contents the next time the page is served. This is performed at the permission level of the web server user.</desc>
	<solution>Disable SSI execution on pages that do not require it. For pages requiring SSI ensure that you perform the following checks
- Only enable the SSI directives that are needed for this page and disable all others.
- HTML entity encode user supplied data before passing it to a page with SSI execution permissions.
- Use SUExec to have the page execute as the owner of the file instead of the web server user.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/SSI-Injection</reference>
	<reference></reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_36>

<vuln_items>wasc_37</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_37>
	<alert>セッション フィクセーション</alert>
	<desc>Session Fixation is an attack technique that forces a user's session ID to an explicit value. Depending on the functionality of the target web site, a number of techniques can be utilized to "fix" the session ID value. These techniques range from Cross-site Scripting exploits to peppering the web site with previously made HTTP requests. After a user's session ID has been fixed, the attacker will wait for that user to login. Once the user does so, the attacker uses the predefined session ID value to assume the same online identity.

Generally speaking there are two types of session management systems when it comes to ID values. The first type is "permissive" systems that allow web browsers to specify any ID. The second type is "strict" systems that only accept server-side-generated values. With permissive systems, arbitrary session IDs are maintained without contact with the web site. Strict systems require the attacker to maintain the "trap-session", with periodic web site contact, preventing inactivity timeouts.

Without active protection against Session Fixation, the attack can be mounted against any web site that uses sessions to identify authenticated users. Web sites using sessions IDs are normally cookie-based, but URLs and hidden form fields are used as well. Unfortunately, cookie-based sessions are the easiest to attack. Most of the currently identified attack methods are aimed toward the fixation of cookies.

In contrast to stealing a users' session IDs after they have logged into a web site, Session Fixation provides a much wider window of opportunity. The active part of the attack takes place before a user logs in.</desc>
	<solution>Invalidate any existing session identifiers prior to authorizing a new user session

For platforms such as ASP that do not generate new values for sessionid cookies, utilize a secondary cookie. In this approach, set a secondary cookie on the user's browser to a random value and set a session variable to the same value. If the session variable and the cookie value ever don't match, invalidate the session, and force the user to log on again.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Session-Fixation</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/384.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_37>

<vuln_items>wasc_38</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_38>
	<alert>URL Redirector Abuse</alert>
	<desc>URL redirectors represent common functionality employed by web sites to forward an incoming request to an alternate resource. This can be done for a variety of reasons and is often done to allow resources to be moved within the directory structure and to avoid breaking functionality for users that request the resource at its previous location. URL redirectors may also be used to implement load balancing, leveraging abbreviated URLs or recording outgoing links. It is this last implementation which is often used in phishing attacks as described in the example below. URL redirectors do not necessarily represent a direct security vulnerability but can be abused by attackers trying to social engineer victims into believing that they are navigating to a site other than the true destination.</desc>
	<solution>Assume all input is malicious. Use an "accept known good" input validation strategy, i.e., use a whitelist of acceptable inputs that strictly conform to specifications. Reject any input that does not strictly conform to specifications, or transform it into something that does. Do not rely exclusively on looking for malicious or malformed inputs (i.e., do not rely on a blacklist). However, blacklists can be useful for detecting potential attacks or determining which inputs are so malformed that they should be rejected outright.

When performing input validation, consider all potentially relevant properties, including length, type of input, the full range of acceptable values, missing or extra inputs, syntax, consistency across related fields, and conformance to business rules. As an example of business rule logic, "boat" may be syntactically valid because it only contains alphanumeric characters, but it is not valid if you are expecting colors such as "red" or "blue."

Use a whitelist of approved URLs or domains to be used for redirection.

Use an intermediate disclaimer page that provides the user with a clear warning that they are leaving your site. Implement a long timeout before the redirect occurs, or force the user to click on the link. Be careful to avoid XSS problems when generating the disclaimer page.

When the set of acceptable objects, such as filenames or URLs, is limited or known, create a mapping from a set of fixed input values (such as numeric IDs) to the actual filenames or URLs, and reject all other inputs.

For example, ID 1 could map to "/login.asp" and ID 2 could map to "http://www.example.com/". Features such as the ESAPI AccessReferenceMap provide this capability.

Understand all the potential areas where untrusted inputs can enter your software: parameters or arguments, cookies, anything read from the network, environment variables, reverse DNS lookups, query results, request headers, URL components, e-mail, files, databases, and any external systems that provide data to the application. Remember that such inputs may be obtained indirectly through API calls.

Many open redirect problems occur because the programmer assumed that certain inputs could not be modified, such as cookies and hidden form fields.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/URL-Redirector-Abuse</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/601.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_38>

<vuln_items>wasc_39</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_39>
	<alert>XPath インジェクション</alert>
	<desc>XPath Injection is an attack technique used to exploit applications that construct XPath (XML Path Language) queries from user-supplied input to query or navigate XML documents. It can be used directly by an application to query an XML document, as part of a larger operation such as applying an XSLT transformation to an XML document, or applying an XQuery to an XML document. The syntax of XPath bears some resemblance to an SQL query, and indeed, it is possible to form SQL-like queries on an XML document using XPath.

If an application uses run-time XPath query construction, embedding unsafe user input into the query, it may be possible for the attacker to inject data into the query such that the newly formed query will be parsed in a way differing from the programmer's intention.</desc>
	<solution>Use parameterized XPath queries (e.g. using XQuery). This will help ensure separation between data plane and control plane.

Properly validate user input. Reject data where appropriate, filter where appropriate and escape where appropriate. Make sure input that will be used in XPath queries is safe in that context.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/XPath-Injection</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/643.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_39>

<vuln_items>wasc_40</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_40>
	<alert>Insufficient Process Validation</alert>
	<desc>Insufficient Process Validation occurs when a web application fails to prevent an attacker from circumventing the intended flow or business logic of the application. When seen in the real world, insufficient process validation has resulted in ineffective access controls and monetary loss.

There are two main types of processes that require validation: flow control and business logic.

"Flow control" refers to multi-step processes that require each step to be performed in a specific order by the user. When an attacker performs the step incorrectly or out of order, the access controls may be bypassed and an application integrity error may occur. Examples of multi-step processes include wire transfer, password recovery, purchase checkout, and account sign-up.

"Business logic" refers to the context in which a process will execute as governed by the business requirements. Exploiting a business logic weakness requires knowledge of the business; if no knowledge is needed to exploit it, then most likely it isn't a business logic flaw. Due to this, typical security measures such as scans and code review will not find this class of weakness. One approach to testing is offered by OWASP in their Testing Guide.</desc>
	<solution>後日発表</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Insufficient-Process-Validation</reference>
	<reference></reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_40>

<vuln_items>wasc_41</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_41>
	<alert>XML Attribute Blowup</alert>
	<desc>XML Attribute Blowup is a denial of service attack against XML parsers. The attacker provides a malicious XML document, which vulnerable XML parsers process in a very inefficient manner, leading to excessive CPU load. The essence of the attack is to include many attributes in the same XML node. Vulnerable XML parsers manage the attributes in an inefficient manner (e.g. in a data container for which insertion of a new attribute has O(n) runtime), resulting in a non-linear (in this example, quadratic, i.e. O(n2)) overall runtime, leading to a denial of service condition via CPU exhaustion.</desc>
	<solution>Design throttling mechanisms into the system architecture. The best protection is to limit the amount of resources that an unauthorized user can cause to be expended. A strong authentication and access control model will help prevent such attacks from occurring in the first place. The login application should be protected against DoS attacks as much as possible. Limiting the database access, perhaps by caching result sets, can help minimize the resources expended. To further limit the potential for a DoS attack, consider tracking the rate of requests received from users and blocking requests that exceed a defined rate threshold.

Mitigation of resource exhaustion attacks requires that the target system either:
 * recognizes the attack and denies that user further access for a given amount of time, or
 * uniformly throttles all requests in order to make it more difficult to consume resources more quickly than they can again be freed. 

The first of these solutions is an issue in itself though, since it may allow attackers to prevent the use of the system by a particular valid user. If the attacker impersonates the valid user, he may be able to prevent the user from accessing the server in question.

The second solution is simply difficult to effectively institute -- and even when properly done, it does not provide a full solution. It simply makes the attack require more resources on the part of the attacker.

Ensure that protocols have specific limits of scale placed on them.

Ensure that all failures in resource allocation place the system into a safe posture.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/XML-Attribute-Blowup</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/400.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_41>

<vuln_items>wasc_42</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_42>
	<alert>機能の悪用</alert>
	<desc>Abuse of Functionality is an attack technique that uses a web site's own features and functionality to attack itself or others. Abuse of Functionality can be described as the abuse of an application's intended functionality to perform an undesirable outcome. These attacks have varied results such as consuming resources, circumventing access controls, or leaking information. The potential and level of abuse will vary from web site to web site and application to application. Abuse of functionality attacks are often a combination of other attack types and/or utilize other attack vectors.</desc>
	<solution>Always utilize APIs in the specified manner.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Abuse-of-Functionality</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/227.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_42>

<vuln_items>wasc_43</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_43>
	<alert>XML External Entities</alert>
	<desc>This technique takes advantage of a feature of XML to build documents dynamically at the time of processing. An XML message can either provide data explicitly or by pointing to an URI where the data exists. In the attack technique, external entities may replace the entity value with malicious data, alternate referrals or may compromise the security of the data the server/XML application has access to.
	Attackers may also use External Entities to have the web services server download malicious code or content to the server for use in secondary or follow on attacks.</desc>
	<solution>後日発表</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/XML-External-Entities</reference>
	<reference></reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_43>

<vuln_items>wasc_44</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_44>
	<alert>XML Entity Expansion</alert>
	<desc>The XML Entity expansion attack, exploits a capability in XML DTDs that allows the creation of custom macros, called entities, that can be used throughout a document. By recursively defining a set of custom entities at the top of a document, an attacker can overwhelm parsers that attempt to completely resolve the entities by forcing them to iterate almost indefinitely on these recursive definitions.

The malicious XML message is used to force recursive entity expansion (or other repeated processing) that completely uses up available server resources.</desc>
	<solution>If possible, prohibit the use of DTDs or use an XML parser that limits the expansion of recursive DTD entities.

Before parsing XML files with associated DTDs, scan for recursive entity declarations and do not continue parsing potentially explosive content.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/XML-Entity-Expansion</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/776.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_44>

<vuln_items>wasc_45</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_45>
	<alert>フィンガー プリント</alert>
	<desc>The most common methodology for attackers is to first footprint the target's web presence and enumerate as much information as possible. With this information, the attacker may develop an accurate attack scenario, which will effectively exploit a vulnerability in the software type/version being utilized by the target host.

Multi-tier fingerprinting is similar to its predecessor, TCP/IP Fingerprinting (with a scanner such as Nmap) except that it is focused on the Application Layer of the OSI model instead of the Transport Layer. The theory behind this fingerprinting is to create an accurate profile of the target's platform, web application software technology, backend database version, configurations and possibly even their network architecture/topology.</desc>
	<solution>後日発表</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Fingerprinting</reference>
	<reference></reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_45>

<vuln_items>wasc_46</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_46>
	<alert>XQuery インジェクション</alert>
	<desc>XQuery Injection is a variant of the classic SQL injection attack against the XML XQuery Language. XQuery Injection uses improperly validated data that is passed to XQuery commands. This inturn will execute commands on behalf of the attacker that the XQuery routines have access to. XQuery injection can be used to enumerate elements on the victim's environment, inject commands to the local host, or execute queries to remote files and data sources. Like SQL injection attacks, the attacker tunnels through the application entry point to target the resource access layer.</desc>
	<solution>Use parameterized queries. This will help ensure separation between data plane and control plane.

Properly validate user input. Reject data where appropriate, filter where appropriate and escape where appropriate. Make sure input that will be used in XQL queries is safe in that context.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/XQuery-Injection</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/652.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_46>

<vuln_items>wasc_47</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_47>
	<alert>不適切なセッション有効期限</alert>
	<desc>Insufficient Session Expiration occurs when a Web application permits an attacker to reuse old session credentials or session IDs for authorization. Insufficient Session Expiration increases a Web site's exposure to attacks that steal or reuse user's session identifiers.

Since HTTP is a stateless protocol, Web sites commonly use cookies to store session IDs that uniquely identify a user from request to request. Consequently, each session ID's confidentiality must be maintained in order to prevent multiple users from accessing the same account. A stolen session ID can be used to view another user's account or perform a fraudulent transaction.

Session expiration is comprised of two timeout types: inactivity and absolute. An absolute timeout is defined by the total amount of time a session can be valid without re-authentication and an inactivity timeout is the amount of idle time allowed before the session is invalidated. The lack of proper session expiration may increase the likelihood of success of certain attacks. A long expiration time increases an attacker's chance of successfully guessing a valid session ID. The longer the expiration time, the more concurrent open sessions will exist at any given time. The larger the pool of sessions, the more likely it will be for an attacker to guess one at random. Although a short session inactivity timeout does not help if a token is immediately used, the short timeout helps to insure that the token is harder to capture while it is still valid.

A Web application should invalidate a session after a predefined idle time has passed (a timeout) and provide the user the means to invalidate their own session, i.e. logout; this helps to keep the lifespan of a session ID as short as possible and is necessary in a shared computing environment where more than one person has unrestricted physical access to a computer. The logout function should be prominently visible to the user, explicitly invalidate a user’s session and disallow reuse of the session token.</desc>
	<solution>Set sessions/credentials expiration date.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Insufficient-Session-Expiration</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/613.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_47>

<vuln_items>wasc_48</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_48>
	<alert>Insecure Indexing</alert>
	<desc>Insecure Indexing is a threat to the data confidentiality of the web-site. Indexing web-site contents via a process that has access to files which are not supposed to be publicly accessible has the potential of leaking information about the existence of such files, and about their content. In the process of indexing, such information is collected and stored by the indexing process, which can later be retrieved (albeit not trivially) by a determined attacker, typically through a series of queries to the search engine. The attacker does not thwart the security model of the search engine. As such, this attack is subtle and very hard to detect and to foil - it’s not easy to distinguish the attacker’s queries from a legitimate user’s queries.</desc>
	<solution>後日発表</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Insecure-Indexing</reference>
	<reference></reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_48>

<vuln_items>wasc_49</vuln_items>
<vuln_item_wasc_49>
	<alert>Insufficient Password Recovery</alert>
	<desc>Insufficient Password Recovery is when a web site permits an attacker to illegally obtain, change or recover another user's password. Conventional web site authentication methods require users to select and remember a password or passphrase. The user should be the only person that knows the password and it must be remembered precisely. As time passes, a user's ability to remember a password fades. The matter is further complicated when the average user visits 20 sites requiring them to supply a password.  (RSA Survey: http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/technology/3639679.stm) Thus, password recovery is an important part in servicing online users.

Examples of automated password recovery processes include requiring the user to answer a "secret question" defined as part of the user registration process. This question can either be selected from a list of canned questions or supplied by the user. Another mechanism in use is having the user provide a "hint" during registration that will help the user remember his password. Other mechanisms require the user to provide several pieces of personal data such as their social security number, home address, zip code etc. to validate their identity. After the user has proven who they are, the recovery system will display or e-mail them a new password.

A web site is considered to have Insufficient Password Recovery when an attacker is able to foil the recovery mechanism being used. This happens when the information required to validate a user's identity for recovery is either easily guessed or can be circumvented. Password recovery systems may be compromised through the use of brute force attacks, inherent system weaknesses, or easily guessed secret questions.</desc>
	<solution>Make sure that all input supplied by the user to the password recovery mechanism is thoroughly filtered and validated

Do not use standard weak security questions and use several security questions.

Make sure that there is throttling on the number of incorrect answers to a security question. Disable the password recovery functionality after a certain (small) number of incorrect guesses.

Require that the user properly answers the security question prior to resetting their password and sending the new password to the e-mail address of record.

Never allow the user to control what e-mail address the new password will be sent to in the password recovery mechanism.

Assign a new temporary password rather than revealing the original password.</solution>
	<reference>http://projects.webappsec.org/Insufficient-Password-Recovery</reference>
	<reference>http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/640.html</reference>
</vuln_item_wasc_49>

</vulnerabilities>